Guide to the Stanford University, Chicana/o Studies, Feminicide Conference Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Chicana/o Studies, Feminicide conference records
2007 May 16-19
SC0898
Stanford University. Center for Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity.
Stanford University. Office of Chicano Affairs.
Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne
0.5 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
The materials were the gift of Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano, 2008.
Information about Access
The materials are open for research use.
Biographical/Historical note
The conference Feminicide = Sanctioned Murder: Gender, Race and Violence in Global Context, held at Stanford University, May 16-19, 2007, was organized by Chicano/o Studies and co-sponsored by the Center for Comparative Studies in Race and Ethnicity. Yvonne Yarbro-Bejarano, chair of Chicana/o Studies, was one of the conference organizers.
Scope and Contents note
The materials document the conference and include flyers, biographies of panelists, video tapes of events (with DVD copies), and digital photographs.
Access Terms
Women--Crimes against.; Women--Violence against.
Collection Contents
- Audiovisual material
  - 8:30AM session, 2007 May 18; 1.01; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.01U)
  - 10AM session, 2007 May 18; 1.02; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.02U)
  - 2-3:45PM Session, 2007 May 18; 1.03; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.03U)
  - 4-5PM Session, 2007 May 18; 1.04; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.04U)
  - 5-7PM Session, 2007 May 18; 1.05; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.05U)
  - 10-12PM session, 2007 May 19; 1.06; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.06U)
  - Lunch meeting, 2007 May 19; 1.07; 1 videotape(s) (MiniDV) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.07U)
  - 2-3:45PM session, 2007 May 19; 1.08; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.08U)
  - 4-5PM session, 2007 May 19; 1.09; 1 videotape(s) (DVCAM) (Box 1)
    - Use copy, 1 optical disc(s) (DVD) (Box 1.09U)
- Photographs, 2007 May 18-19; 842 computer file(s) (JPG)
- Brochures and speaker bios (Box 1, Folder 1)
General Note
Additional materials from the conference can be found in the Stanford Archives Museum Collection under the call number ARCH-AM 2008-028.